FRANCHESKA GUZMÁN FLORES

Software Tester | Web Developer



Carolina, PR



787-410-9414



francheska.dev



francheska-guzman@outlook.com

About

Francheska is an ISTQB U.S. Certified Software Tester with over 6 years of combined experience in quality assurance, software testing, and web development. Strong analytical skills, detail-oriented, problem solver, and interpersonal abilities.

Skills

Coding

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Libraries and Frameworks

React.js, Node.js, Express.js, jQuery, Cypress.io

Languages

Spanish (native), English (intermediate)

Databases

SQL, PostgreSQL, RESTful API

Hosting, CMS and Cloud Services

Git/GitHub, WordPress, Heroku, Azure DevOps

Usability/Accessibility Tools

Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite, Wave

Work Experience

Quality Assurance Tester

INVID LLC - Information Technology Company

Oct 2019 - Present

San Juan, PR

- Participate in the process of the Software Development Life Cycle (Scrum).
- Create test plans, test suites, and test cases in Azure Test Plans.
- Run manual tests and perform exploratory testing in web and mobile applications.
- Conduct usability/accessibility testing for WCAG 2.1, ADA, and Section 508 compliance by using tools such as the Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite, and Wave.
- Report and track issues identified during testing activities to ensure defect resolution and testing completion.
- · Collaborate in the development of new ideas to resolve system's issues and improve current
- Contribute in the creation of guidelines to improve internal QA/QC procedures.
- Provide training about manual testing activities.

Front End Web Developer

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

New York Film Academy - School of Film and Acting

New York, NY

- · Coded e-mail marketing campaigns and landing pages based on mockups and provided content.
- Segmented mailing lists by making queries on the database.
- Delivered approved e-mail campaigns to the target market using both Campaigner and iContact e-mail marketing automation platforms.
- Made updates to the New York Film Academy websites and WordPress sites.
- Coded the new version of the online applications.
- Debugged e-mail campaigns, landing pages, online applications, and websites.
- · Kept track of workflows on Asana and worked closely with the Development, Design, and Marketing teams.

Web Developer Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

Second Language Design - Creative and Marketing Agency

New York, NY

- Maintained active communication with the team of designers, developers, and clients such as The North Carolina State University's College of Veterinary Medicine (https://painfreecats.org) and Acupuncture Remedies (https://aprpc.com).
- Developed WordPress sites for clients based on mockups and provided content.
- Performed QA testing across modern platforms and devices.
- Added meta tags for SEO and set up Google Analytics.
- Used Google Spreadsheets API for data collection.
- Delivered the website to the client in their private hosting provider.

Software Tester Sep 2014 - Jul 2018

uTest - Crowdsourced Software Testing Community

Remote

- Executed test cases in web and native applications.
- Performed exploratory testing to identify any GUI, functional, or technical bug.
- Performed localization testing by verifying translations from English to Latin American Spanish.
- Performed regression testing.
- · Submitted detailed bug reports.

Projects

Weather Forecast

https://francheska-guzman.github.io/weather-forecast

Weather Forecast is a web app that provides information such as temperature, pressure, and humidity of five cities. Developed with React.js and requesting the data from a third party API.

Check out my GitHub account for more projects: https://github.com/francheska-guzman

Education

Web Development Immersive Program Certificate of Completion General Assembly 2017 New York, NY

Web Development CodeBridge Program2017Certificate of CompletionBronx, NYPer Scholas

Bachelor of Business Administration2015Accounting and Office Systems AdministrationSan Juan, PRUniversity of Puerto Rico, Río Piedras Campus

Certification

Certified Tester, Foundation Level (CTFL)

American Software Testing Qualifications Board, Inc. Credential ID: 21-CTFL-01698-USA Issued Sep 2021 - No Expiration Date